# **Alisson Ricardo**

Las Vegas, NV 89108 | 702-635-2812 | alissonricardo68@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

#### **GAME PROGRAMMER**

Passionate about front-end designing, testing, and back-end development – especially with Javascript. Built out 4 projects from scratch – 2 full stack and 2 front end – while continuing to build in and learn React Native & C++ independently. Previous professional experience in customer service has brought on versatile collaborative and organizational skills with peers of all backgrounds, in all situations.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Libraries and Frameworks: React, Express.js, Jquery, Bootstrap, Material UI, Bulma, Materialize, Flask

Databases and other: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful Routing, JSON API

Interpersonal skills: Communication, Decision-Making, Active Listening, Teamwork, Positive Attitude,

Self-Learning, Time Management, Customer/Client Empathy

#### **PROJECTS**

## Gamers, On Record - GitHub - Python | React | Material UI | Flask | Node.js

Full CRUD app with a gaming API where users can log in to share posts about games or browse through them.

- Implemented back-end services with CRUD capabilities, user authentication, and API endpoint requests.
- Used new skills doing this second project with React, like Context Providers and Hooks, that made the passing of properties throughout components more efficient.
- Taught myself to use Material UI with React, making styling a lot of the components simpler and neater.

## The Music Box - GitHub - Node.js | Mongoose | EJS | Express | Bulma

Full CRUD app where people can share music and add to the collection page to browse through.

- Built back-end services to allow for users to post, delete, or update data into the app.
- Wrote code that could handle processing real time data entered by a user about their song/album.
- Styled a clean UI and interface for users to browse and submit/update any of the data in the app.

#### Pot Smash Simulator '97 - GitHub - CSS | JavaScript | Canvas

HTML5 Canvas game where you play as a character that tries destroying as many pots in a certain timeframe.

- Learned a new API (Canvas) independently to create the displayed area and logic for the game.
- Designed a simple but efficient UI for the player to see the stats, time left, and gameplay.
- Animated movement for the player using key presses and waves of enemies coming down from the screen!

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Target - Guest Advocate**

Current

> Created a welcoming experience for and connection with hundreds of guests while maintaining the store's best practices. Fulfilled services for guests efficiently and performed tasks for multiple areas of the store.

#### **Asurion - Tech Support Rep**

05/2020 - 09/2021

Managed 60 - 80 customer chats daily and increased monthly home insurance sales by 10% with the team. Additionally, raised bug concerns and feature requests to the development team as needed.

### **Sykes - Tech Support Rep**

10/2018 - 05/2020

➤ Delivered premier customer experience to 40 - 50 PlayStation players via chat/phone per day, significant involvement in maintaining services and relaying info on products, services, billing, and more.

#### Petco - Guest Advisor

04/2017 - 10/2018

➤ Provided guests excellent customer service, subject matter expert on all products & services, and ensured health and wellness of over 100 animals – ensuring operational standards were maintained.

#### **EDUCATION**